# Jeeva R

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



jeevasmart82@gmail.com



7200712356



linkedin.com/in/jeevasmart82

## **Summary**

IT Professional with over 3.8 years of IT Support Technician experience as a Freelancer.

I am a self-motivated and well-organized guy looking for a chance to put my skills to good use. With excellent analytical abilities and a track record of quickly identifying and resolving technological difficulties.

Strong knowledge of Windows server, VMware, DNS, DHCP, WEBSERVER, LINUX, and MAC.

## **Experience**



#### Freelance

## Self Employed

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022 (8 months)

- 1. Windows Server 2019 installation and configuration.
- 2. Working with ADDS, DNS, DHCP, WDS, HYPER-V, and VMWARE.
- 3.Good in FTP, File Server, Permissions, Local File Sharing, and Port Forwarding.
- 4. Setting up a new web server (XAMPP SERVER).
- 5.Set up REMOTE ACCESS VPN on the server in 2019.
- 6.Understanding of Windows OS,Installation, Formatting, Partitioning, Configuration, and Troubleshooting.
- 7. Understanding of LINUX (Ubuntu) and Apple devices such as the iMac, Mac Mini, and iPad.
- 8. Outlook Assistance (Configure & troubleshooting MS Outlook).
- 9.In-depth knowledge of the client's operating system (Windows 7, Windows 10 and windows 11).
- 10.Email Management: Creating and managing email user accounts and data using CRM.
- 11. Setting up and sharing network printers.
- 12. Maintaining the software and hardware asset management.
- 13. Server maintenance, data backups, and MYSQL database backups.
- 14. Troubleshooting and resolving client system issues.
- 15. Maintenance of CCTV cameras, unmanaged switches, and routers provided by the ISP.
- 16. Managing the Microsoft Office as well as other client-side system needs.
- 17. Network Administration: Static IP and DHCP Configuration.
- 18. Setting up DNS and DDNS.
- 19.A basic understanding of VMware ESXI and NAS Server (Not Implemented).

## y IT Support Technician

Freelancer.com

Feb 2017 - Mar 2020 (3 years 2 months)

- 1.Installation of the operating system (OS) and Driver updates.
- 2. Troubleshooting hardware and software issues.
- 3. Unlocking and Flashing of all mobile phones.
- 4. Reset the passwords for all operating systems (OS) (WINDOWS, LINUX, IMAC).
- 5.Install and maintain equipment and software.
- 6. Hands-on experience with Windows/Linux/Mac OS environments.

- 7. Setting up a printer and sharing it.
- 8.ISP Routers and Switches Configuration.
- 9. Troubleshoot network and system issues.
- 10.Installation, configuration, and troubleshooting of LANs and WLANs.
- 11.Installing anti-virus software and removing viruses.

#### **Education**

Kings Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Engineering Aug 2017 - Aug 2021

Arignar Anna Government Higher Secondary School

Higher Secondary School Certificate, Computer Science Jun 2015 - May 2017

Sri Saraswathi Vidhya Mandir Matriculation School

Secondary School Leaving Certificate Jun 2014 - May 2015

### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) Blue Ball Technologies
- iT Fundamentals & Computer Networking Course with Comptia A+ Udemy
- Fundamentals of IT Helpdesk Freshservice
- Computer Basics 2022 Basic Computer Skills And Fundamentals Udemy UC-4499db11-8f3e-4ec7-9c34-d55f293fab54
- G Linux Tutorial Great Learning

#### Skills

Windows Server • Server Architecture • Linux Server • Domain Name System (DNS) • Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) • System Administration • VMWare ESXi • VMware vSphere • VMware Infrastructure • Amazon Web Services (AWS)